Preliminary Guide to the North Carolina Poverty Project Records, 1983-2004 and undated (bulk 1986-1997)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
North Carolina Poverty Project records 1983-2004 and undated (bulk 1986-1997)
North Carolina Poverty Project
30.1 linear feet Extent: 19,182 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00937
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The North Carolina Poverty Project Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2002.
Biographical Note
Non-profit organization incorporated January 7, 1987, to study, provide education about, and stimulate action on the causes of poverty in North Carolina. In 2000, merged with other organizations to form the Poverty Coalition.
Collection Overview
Primarily consists of Executive Board and Sector and Advisory Groups correspondence, memoranda, and meeting records; financial and planning documents, including grant applications; and workshop, seminar, and presentation materials that document the organization's activities to raise awareness of and promote action on the causes of poverty in N.C. Also includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, and other writings by the executive director, J. Gordon Chamberlin; telephone logs and appointment books; various printed material concerning poverty in NC; 11 audio and 15 videocassettes; 134 black-and-white and 10 color prints; 10 color negatives; and 8 data cartridge tapes. (02-234)
The 2006 addition (2006-0055)(600 items, 1.3 lin. ft.; dated 1986-2004) contains correspondence, meeting records, publications, and other documents generated by the North Carolina Poverty Project and the Poverty Coalition. Also included is an oversize 7 panel Poverty Display.
The 2007 addition (2007-0023)(3300 items, 4.4 lin. ft.; dated 1982-2003) contains documents related to the executive board including correspondence, financial documents, and planning documents; tax information; documents related to conferences and business trips; photocopies and clippings of articles related to poverty from the New York Times and other newspapers (1986-2001); and lists of library holdings of poverty books at Southeastern universities.
Subject Headings
Chamberlin, J. Gordon; North Carolina Poverty Project; Nonprofit organizations -- North Carolina; Public welfare -- North Carolina; Poverty -- North Carolina; Poverty -- Research -- North Carolina; North Carolina -- Economic conditions; Memoranda; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Color negatives; Machine-readable records; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2002-0234
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - NCPP Board correspondence, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Board members correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - NCPP Board of Directors correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
    - Board lists for Robert W. Scott, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Board--Legal
      - NCPP By-Laws, revised, 1990 (Box 1)
      - NCPP Incorporation papers, 1987-1990 (Box 1)
    - Board--Meetings, 1986-1992 (Box 1)
    - Foundations [appeals and responses], 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Foundations [appeals and responses] continued, 1987-1994 (Box 2)
      Includes folders for individual foundations, B-K.
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Foundations [appeals and responses] continued, 1987-1994 (Box 3)
      Includes folders for individual foundations, K-W.
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Fundraising Activity Files, 1988-1994 (Box 4)
      Includes correspondence, planning records, and records of contributors.
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Accounts, 1988-1992 (Box 5)
      Includes accounting, general ledger, and operations reports; budgets and budget preparation; and sales.
    - Expenses, 1987-1994 (Box 5)
      Includes expense reports, lease agreements, payroll, and tax forms and reports.
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Personnel Policies, [ca. 1991] (Box 6)
      Includes information compiled by J. Gordon Chamberlin and presentations made by Nelson Stover.
    - Staff Meetings and Activities, 1986-1991 (Box 6)
    - NCPP Beginnings
      - Education coordinators, 1986 October-1990 November (Box 6)
      - Human Services Institute, 1986 March- 1987 August (Box 6)
      - Poverty Project Committee, 1986 November-1987 April (Box 6)
    - J. Gordon Chamberlin Articles, Correspondence, Papers, and Presentations, 1987-1992 (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - J. Gordon Chamberlin, continued (Box 7)
      Includes material relating to the NCPP crisis, 1992; NCPP description, aims, and handouts; and records from the NCPP Information Center.
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Professional Advisory Group memoranda and correspondence, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
    - Publicity, reviews, and news releases, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
    - Sector and Advisory Groups
      - General (Box 8)
      - Ralph Ketner correspondence, 1986 May- 1990 October (Box 8)
      - Business Sector, 1993 (Box 8)
      - Charlotte, 1991 September 3-1992 April 23 (Box 8)
      - Charlotte Business, 1990 December -1991 March (Box 8)
      - County Commissioners, 1986-1988 (Box 8)
      - Editors Sector, 1986-1988 (Box 8)
      - Human Services Sector, 1986 (Box 8)
      - Lawyers Sector, 1986-1988 (Box 8)
      - Lawyers and Poverty, 1988-1991 (Box 8)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Sector and Advisory Groups, continued
      - Legislators (Box 9)
      - Librarians Sector (Box 9)
      - Medical/dental Sector, 1987 May 4 (Box 9)
      - Poverty and health, 1988 December-1990 February (Box 9)
      - Poverty programs (Box 9)
      - Representatives meeting (Box 9)
      - Public school superintendents, 1986-1989 (Box 9)
      - Religious Sector (Box 9)
      - Rural Sector, 1986 July - 1987 January (Box 9)
      - Thrift Organizations Sector (Box 9)
      - Structure of the NCPP (Box 9)
      - Television Sector (Box 9)
      - NCPP Toner Scam (Box 9)
    - Subject files, including memoranda, correspondence, and other materials, A-Ch, 1984-1994 (Box 9)
  - Contents of Box 10: (Box 10)
    - Subject files, including memoranda, correspondence, and other materials, Co-E, 1984-1994 (Box 10)
  - Contents of Box 11 (Box 11)
    - Subject files, including memoranda, correspondence, and other materials, F-I, 1984-1994 (Box 11)
      Contains section of folders on Individual Donors, approximately fifty names.
  - Contents of Box 12: (Box 12)
    - Subject files, including memoranda, correspondence, and other materials, Individuals, continued, 1984-1994 (Box 12)
  - Contents of Box 13: (Box 13)
    - Subject files, including memoranda, correspondence, and other materials, Individuals, continued, and then J-Sm, 1984-1994 (Box 13)
  - Contents of Box 14: (Box 14)
    - Subject files, including memoranda, correspondence, and other materials, So-We, 1984-1994 (Box 14)
  - Contents of Box 15: (Box 15)
    - Subject files, including memoranda, correspondence, and other materials, Wi-Wr, 1984-1994 (Box 15)
    - Board Correspondence [relating to NCPP publications], 1987-1990 (Box 15)
  - Contents of Box 16: (Box 16)
    - Board Correspondence continued (Box 16)
    - NCPP Publications
      - Causes of Poverty (Box 16)
      - 25 Years of Community Action in North Carolina (Box 16)
      - Examining Poverty (Box 16)
      - Finding Out about The Other North Carolina (Box 16)
      - Underlying Issues for the Rural Summit (Box 16)
      - Finding Out About Poverty in North Carolina (Box 16)
      - Influential Sectors Program-- The General Plan (Box 16)
      - Helping Students Study Poverty: Suggestions to teachers (Box 16)
      - How We Feed the Poor (Box 16)
      - I Have Walked: Stories and Poems about Poverty (Box 16)
      - North Carolinians Write about Poverty (Box 16)
      - The Poor Among Us: A View of Poverty in North Carolina (Box 16)
      - Poverty and Civic Responsibility: A Statement to all North Carolinians (Box 16)
      - Poverty in the East: Shared Ownership in the Problems and Solutions (Box 16)
      - Poverty Project Exploration: State Advisory Groups (Box 16)
      - Poverty Project Exploration: Report (Box 16)
      - Exploration and Replication: A Report (Box 16)
      - North Carolina Poverty Project: Replication Handbook, 1993 (Box 16)
      - Causes of Poverty (Box 16)
      - 19 Reasons for being in Poverty (Box 16)
      - Poverty Study Packet: Resource Material for Various Ways to Study Poverty (Box 16)
      - Superintendents Discuss Impacts of Poverty on Public Schools, 1987 (Box 16)
      - Thinking About Poverty (Box 16)
    - Influential Sectors Program, 1991-1993 (Box 16)
      Includes minutes of meetings.
  - Contents of Box 17: (Box 17)
    - Influential Sectors Program continued, 1991-1993 (Box 17)
      General information including minutes of meetings, correspondence, information on and for participants.
    - ISP Individual Sectors
      - Academia Council, 1986-1993 (Box 17)
      - Business and Advisory Council, 1992 (Box 17)
      - Business and Poverty Council, 1991 (Box 17)
  - Contents of Box 18: (Box 18)
    - ISP Individual Sectors, continued
      - Business Rotary Club Responses Report, 1987 October 13 (Box 18)
      - Foundations Council, 1990-1993 (Box 18)
    - Foundations and Poverty Council, 1992
      - Government Council, 1992 June- 1993 January (Box 18)
      - Government and Poverty Council, 1986-1992 May (Box 18)
      - The Poor and Poverty Council, 1990-1992 (Box 18)
      - Poverty Programs and Council, 1990-1992 (Box 18)
      - Religion and Poverty Council Committee on Principles (Box 18)
      - Religion and Poverty Council Committee on Theology and Ethics, 1992-1993 (Box 18)
      - Religion and Poverty Council, 1991-1992 (Box 18)
  - Contents of Box 19: (Box 19)
    - ISP Individual Sectors, continued
      - Religion and Poverty Council continued, 1987-1992 (Box 19)
        Includes general information including minutes of meetings, study groups, council nominees, questionnaires, correspondence, and task forces.
    - Coalition Addressing Systemic Poverty
      - General Information including articles, papers, and correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 19)
  - Contents of Box 20: (Box 20)
    - Coalition Addressing Systemic Poverty, continued
      - Workshops, 1992-1994 (Box 20)
      - Member States
        - Alabama (Box 20)
        - Arkansas (Box 20)
        - Georgia (Box 20)
        - Kentucky (Box 20)
        - Louisiana (Box 20)
        - Mississippi (Box 20)
  - Contents of Box 21: (Box 21)
    - Coalition Addressing Systemic Poverty, continued
      - Member States, continued
        - Mississippi resource file (Box 21)
    - Correspondence Seminar on Understanding Poverty, 1997-1998 (Box 21)
    - NCPP Income, 2001 (Box 21)
    - State Tax records, 2001 (Box 21)
  - Contents of Box 22: (Box 22)
    - NCPP--IRS, 1987-1999 (Box 22)
    - Causes of Poverty (Box 22)
    - Material for repository (Box 22)
    - Anti-slavery (Box 22)
    - Professional advisory group, 1987-1996 (Box 22)
    - Originals of working papers, 1990 (Box 22)
    - NCPP Beginnings, 1986 March- 1987 January 5 (Box 22)
    - Expenses, 1998 (Box 22)
    - Fundraising, 1994-1997 (Box 22)
    - Smith Richardson (Box 22)
    - NCPP folder (Box 22)
    - Expenditures, 2000 (Box 22)
  - Contents of Box 23: (Box 23)
    - Workshop 3, 1993 March 4-7 (Box 23)
    - NC maps (Box 23)
    - Social Work Forum, 1983 April 12 (Box 23)
    - Publications (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - NCPP beginnings
      - Advisory council, 1984-1985 (Box 23)
      - Issues advisory group, 1986 (Box 23)
    - The Human Services Institute
      - Board of Trustees, 1984 May- 1985 May (Box 23)
      - Consultations (Box 23)
      - Dinner, 1985 December 10 (Box 23)
      - Subgroup on Community Social Policy (Box 23)
      - Staff Training and Leadership Development (Box 23)
      - Program on Poverty (Box 23)
      - Statement of Principles (Box 23)
    - Executive seminar, 1983-1986 (Box 23)
  - Contents of Box 24: (Box 24)
    - Forsyth County (Box 24)
    - Chamberlin--Seminar (Box 24)
    - The Human Services Institute
      - Trustees education program (Box 24)
      - Research committee (Box 24)
      - Board, 1984 (Box 24)
      - Advisory council (Box 24)
      - Board accounts (Box 24)
    - Peacemaker (Box 24)
    - Rick Gentry (Box 24)
    - Executives seminar, 1983-1984 (Box 24)
    - Philosophy subgroup (Box 24)
    - NCPP beginnings--Sector strategy group, 1986 (Box 24)
    - HSI (Box 24)
    - HSI--Education project follow-up (Box 24)
  - Contents of Box 24A: (Box 24A)
    - Chamberlin--minutes of board meetings, 1985-1986 (Box 24A)
  - Contents of Box 25: (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous digital and audiovisual material including videocassettes of panels, evaluations, and presentations. (Box 25)
  - Contents of Box 27: (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous digital and audiovisual material, continued (Box 26)
  - Contents of Box 27: (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous audiovisual material, continued (Box 27)
    - Rolodex contents (Box 27)
  - Contents of Box 28: (Box 28)
    - Board Member Photos (Box 28)
    - Anniversary Brochure (Box 28)
    - Photo of Senator Terry Sanford (Box 28)
    - Poverty photos by Eric Green (Box 28)
    - North Carolina Insight--Profiles in Poverty: State Policy and Poor in North Carolina, 1989 April (Box 28)
  - Contents of Box 29: (Box 29)
    - Leadership Development in the South, 1992 (Box 29)
    - Academia response cards (Box 29)
    - [Loose material: Influential Sectors Program] (Box 29)
  - Contents of Box 30: (Box 30)
    - [Loose material: Influential Sectors Program] (Box 30)
    - Complete mailing list (Box 30)
    - Leaders correspondence, 1992 (Box 30)
    - NC Low Income Housing Coalition--Planning retreat, 1991 October 3-4 (Box 30)
    - Mailing lists sorted by zip code (Box 30)
    - CrossRoads of Wilmington Incorporated (Box 30)
    - Williams Report (Box 30)
    - C/F Study--Access to Prenatal and Maternity Care by County, 1985-1989 (Box 30)
  - Contents of Box 31: (Box 31)
    - Human Services Project--Lists of names (Box 31)
    - Mailing list--current (Box 31)
    - Mailing list names (Box 31)
    - Coalition on Addressing Systemic Poverty, member states
      - Tennessee (Box 31)
      - West Virginia (Box 31)
      - West Virginia resource file (Box 31)
      - Pennsylvania (Box 31)
      - South Carolina (Box 31)
      - South Carolina resource file (Box 31)
    - Category lists--computer (Box 31)
    - Correspondence to college professors for 1987 publication support, 1987 (Box 31)
    - Mailing list add-ons and returned envelopes (Box 31)
    - Lists (Box 31)
    - CAA anniversary booklet (Box 31)
    - [Unlabeled folder: mailing list] (Box 31)
  - Contents of Box 32: (Box 32)
    - Newsletter mailing list (Box 32)
    - Poverty and health (Box 32)
    - [Miscellaneous loose and unlabeled material] (Box 32)
    - CAA [Community Action Agencies] Anniversary Booklet invoices (Box 32)
    - CAA 25th Anniversary (Box 32)
    - CAA Anniversary Booklet--Specific grant (Box 32)
    - Singular statements re poverty (Box 32)
    - CPS #1953 (Box 32)
    - [Unlabeled folders] (Box 32)
    - [Miscellaneous loose material] (Box 32)
  - Contents of Box 33: (Box 33)
    - [Miscellaneous loose material] (Box 33)
    - Smith Richardson application (Box 33)
    - Niblock/Ramey (Box 33)
    - Legislators Education Program (Box 33)
    - Children/Families
      - Consultations I and II (Box 33)
      - Report on Consultation I (Box 33)
      - Working groups final lists (Box 33)
      - Legislators Education Program (Box 33)
      - Television Documentary (Box 33)
      - Working group
        - Case studies (Box 33)
        - Detrimental legislation (Box 33)
      - In poverty (Box 33)
  - Contents of Box 34: (Box 34)
    - Community Action Agencies Program (Box 34)
    - Community Action groups (Box 34)
    - Legal Services Booklet (Box 34)
    - Poverty Materials Center (Box 34)
    - REDC
      - Poverty task force (Box 34)
      - Strategic Planning conference, 1990 (Box 34)
      - Source book (Box 34)
  - Contents of Box 35: (Box 35)
    - REDC, continued
      - Source book (Box 35)
      - Source book corrections (Box 35)
      - Inventory of data/information about poverty--expenses (Box 35)
      - Advisory committee--Inventory of poverty data/information (Box 35)
      - CAP reports (Box 35)
      - DSS reports (Box 35)
      - United Way reports (Box 35)
      - Bill Finger--Governmental (Box 35)
      - David Lee Stegall--Academia and private organization (Box 35)
      - Sandra Hopkins--Bibliographical (Box 35)
      - Done (Box 35)
      - To be called (Box 35)
      - To call back (Box 35)
      - Inventory report forms (Box 35)
      - Finding Out About the Other North Carolina (Box 35)
  - Contents of Box 36: (Box 36)
    - Logs
      - 1989-1990 (Box 36)
      - 1989-1994 (Box 36)
      - 1988 (Box 36)
      - 1987 (Box 36)
  - Contents of Box 37: (Box 37)
    - Log, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Appointments, 1988-1991 (Box 37)
    - ISP Council Notes, 1992 (Box 37)
    - Notes on Replication Handbook (Box 37)
    - Poverty Project Workshop II, 1992 (Box 37)
    - [Poverty Project] Workshops, 1993 (Box 37)
    - Human Services Institute (HSI), [ca. 1984] (Box 37)
  - Contents of Box 38: (Box 38)
    - Coalition Workshop IV, 1993-1994 (Box 38)
    - Coalition Workshop VII, 1993-1994 (Box 38)
    - Board, 1995-1999 (Box 38)
    - The Role of Religious Communities and Poverty--Responses 1-75 (Box 38)
    - The Role of Religious Communities and Poverty--Responses 76-108 (Box 38)
  - Contents of Box 39: (Box 39)
    - Foundation Grants to Affect Poverty, 1992 (Box 39)
    - [Miscellaneous unlabeled material] (Box 39)
    - Influential Sectors Program, 1990 (Box 39)
    - ACED (Box 39)
    - BUS (Box 39)
    - Poor (Box 39)
    - FND (Box 39)
    - [Miscellaneous unlabeled material] (Box 39)
  - Contents of Box 40: (Box 40)
    - PPRO (Box 40)
    - REL, 1991-1992 (Box 40)
    - NCPP Theology and Ethics Committee of the ISP Religion and Poverty Council (Box 40)
    - NCPP Board
      - 1987-1990 (Box 40)
      - 1991-1994 (Box 40)
    - NCPP study packet (Box 40)
  - Contents of Box 41: (Box 41)
    - NCPP (Box 41)
    - The Poor Among Us (Box 41)
    - The Poor Among Us--Clippings (Box 41)
    - The Poor Among Us--Clippings List (Box 41)
    - [Miscellaneous loose material] (Box 41)
    - The Pilot (Box 41)
- Accession, 2006 (2006-0055), 3 boxes
  The 2006 addition (600 items, 1.3 lin. ft.; dated 1986-2004) contains correspondence, meeting records, publications, and other documents generated by the North Carolina Poverty Project and the Poverty Coalition. Also included is an oversize 7 panel Poverty Display.
  - Upon Whom We Depend (Box 42)
  - Pamphlets and booklets published by North Carolina Poverty Project Publications
    - North Carolina Poverty Project, 1990 (Box 42)
    - Rumors and Facts About Poverty, 1990 (Box 42)
    - 19 Reasons for Being in Poverty, April 1986 (Box 42)
    - Poverty and Civic Responsibility, December 1987 (Box 42)
    - North Carolinians Write About Poverty, March 1988 (Box 42)
    - Thinking About Poverty, by professors of economics, education, ethics, public health, history, political science, psychology, social work, sociology, and a lawyer, May 1988, I Have Walked, March 1989 (Box 42)
    - How We Feed the Poor in North Carolina, August 1989 (Box 42)
    - Finding Out About the Other North Carolina, September 1989 (Box 42)
    - Poverty in the East, March 1990 (Box 42)
    - Causes of Poverty, 1994 (Box 42)
    - Community Action in North Carolina, 1994 (Box 42)
    - Program on Understanding Poverty, Academic Year 1999 (Box 42)
    - First Report - Program on Understanding Poverty, 2000 (Box 42)
    - Second Report - Program on Understanding Poverty, 2000 (Box 42)
    - Display Folders (Box 42)
    - On Understanding Poverty (Box 42)
    - Why Don't United Methodists Address What Causes the Social Injustice of Employee Poverty (Box 42)
    - Poverty Coalition Conference, 2003 (Box 42)
  - Materials for Understanding Poverty Basic Course (Box 43)
  - Materials for Correspondence Course (Box 43)
  - Documentation of the Poverty Coalition, 1994-1998 (Box 43)
    Includes correspondence, board minutes, budget reports, and progress reports.
  - Documentation of the Poverty Coalition, 1998-2000 (Box 43)
  - Documentation of the Poverty Coalition, 2001-2004 (Box 43)
  - Poverty Coalition Updates (Box 43)
  - The Poverty Display (Box 44)
    Seven foam board panels.
- Accession, 2007 (2007-0023), 3 boxes
  The 2007 addition (2007-0023)(3300 items, 4.4 lin. ft.; dated 1982-2003) contains documents related to the executive board including correspondence, financial documents, and planning documents; tax information; documents related to conferences and business trips; photocopies and clippings of articles related to poverty from the New York Times and other newspapers (1986-2001); and lists of library holdings of poverty books at Southeastern universities.
  - Documents from board meetings (Box 45)
    Including minutes, reports, and correspondence (2000-2001)
  - Photocopies of articles (Box 45)
  - Poverty Coalition incorporation documents (Box 45)
  - Documentation from the Mott Foundation (Box 45)
  - Pamphlets and booklets by related organizations (Box 45)
  - Other documents related to the Poverty Coalition (Box 45)
  - Documents about related organizations (Box 46)
  - Documents related to conferences and trips (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 46)
  - Poverty Coalition Board documents, 2000-2007 (Box 46)
  - Poverty Coalition tax information and forms (Box 46)
  - 501 C-3 documentation (Box 46)
  - Correspondence (Box 47)
  - 3 and 5 year plans (Box 47)
  - Documents of recent publications (Box 47)
  - Statistics reports (Box 47)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 48)
  - Documents about related organizations (Box 48)
  - Publications by related organizations (Box 48)
  - Information on Universities in the Southeast (Box 48)
  - Statistics reports (Box 49)
  - Files related to conferences and trips (Box 49)
  - Photocopies and clippings of newspaper articles (Box 49)
  - Documents about related organizations (Box 49)
  - Correspondence with related organizations and professors (Box 50)
  - Correspondence with related organizations and professors (Box 50)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2003, numbered 1-579 by the donor (Box 51)
  - 42 3.5" Diskettes (Box 51)
    Diskettes have been removed from this box and their contents have been migrated to the server.
    Original digital media in this series requires further processing before use. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use these materials.
  - Poverty Coalition Executive Committee Workbook, 2000 (Box 52)
  - List of poverty books from Barnes and Noble (Box 52)
  - University library holdings for books related to poverty from:
    - Auburn University (Box 52)
    - University of South Carolina (Box 52)
    - Clemson University (Box 52)
    - College of Charleston (Box 52)
    - Samford (Box 52)
    - UNC Charlotte (Box 52)
    - USC Spartanburg (Box 52)
    - Duke University (Box 52)
    - East Carolina University (Box 52)
    - North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University (Box 52)
    - Alabama Agricultural and Mechanical University (Box 52)